<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>coordination on Miss Amanda</title>
    <link>https://missamanda.blog/skills/coordination/</link>
    <description>Recent content in coordination on Miss Amanda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:32:05 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://missamanda.blog/skills/coordination/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Dusting</title>
      <link>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/practical-life/care-of-environment/dusting/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/practical-life/care-of-environment/dusting/</guid>
      <description>Materials: One basket with appropriate dust cloths and an area to dust.
Presentation:  Invite the child to dust. Carry basket of dust cloths to an area in need of dusting. With dominant hand, grasp dust cloth. Start at the top left corner. Wipe toward top right. Move down and again repeat left to right wiping motion. Continue in this manner until area has been properly and evenly dusted. Look at dust cloth.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Floor Sweeping</title>
      <link>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/practical-life/care-of-environment/floor-sweeping/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/practical-life/care-of-environment/floor-sweeping/</guid>
      <description>Materials: Child-sized broom, hand broom, short handled dustpan, an area of floor marked off for sweeping, material to be swept (paper shavings, elbow macaroni, beans, etc.), and a garbage can.
Presentation:   Invite the child to sweep.
  Carry a basket filled with the materials to be swept (macaroni) to an area of the floor marked off for sweeping.
  Grasp one handful of elbow macaroni. Slowly and gracefully sprinkle them on the floor.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower of Cubes</title>
      <link>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/sensorial/visual/tower-of-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:32:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/sensorial/visual/tower-of-cubes/</guid>
      <description>Tower of Cubes
  Materials: Ten solid wooden cubes the largest of which is 10 cm3 the smallest of which is 1 cm3. Each cube decreases in size by 1 cm3.
Presentation:   Invite the child to work with the tower of cubes.
  Obtain and unroll a rug in the accepted manner.
  Walk to the area of the room containing the tower of cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>