<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>HOME on Miss Amanda</title>
    <link>http://missamanda.blog/</link>
    <description>Recent content in HOME on Miss Amanda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 12:01:58 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://missamanda.blog/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Role of the Teacher</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/blog/role-of-the-teacher/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 01 Apr 2020 12:01:58 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/blog/role-of-the-teacher/</guid>
      <description>&lt;figure class=&#34;right&#34;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&#34;http://missamanda.blog/Montessori.png&#34; width=&#34;150px&#34;/&gt; 
&lt;/figure&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Maria Montessori wrote that, “In brief, the teacher’s principle duty in the school may be described as follows: She should explain the use of the material. She is the main
connecting link between the material, that is, the objects, and the child. This is a simple, modest duty&amp;hellip;”&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>I Spy Games</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/language/exploration-of-sound-and-symbol/i-spy-games/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 14:38:39 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/language/exploration-of-sound-and-symbol/i-spy-games/</guid>
      <description>Materials: Objects that use the 40 key sounds / phonemes (see Key Sounds) and contains only 3 of these sounds per object/word.
Presentation I Beginning Sounds  Invite a small group of children to join you. Bring the basket of objects from the shelf to a work rug. Sit in a small group. Ask each child to choose one object from the basket and hold it in their hand. Name the selected objects with the children.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Tower of Cubes</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/sensorial/visual/tower-of-cubes/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Mar 2020 18:32:05 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/lesson-plans/sensorial/visual/tower-of-cubes/</guid>
      <description>Tower of Cubes
  Materials: Ten solid wooden cubes the largest of which is 10 cm3 the smallest of which is 1 cm3. Each cube decreases in size by 1 cm3.
Presentation:   Invite the child to work with the tower of cubes.
  Obtain and unroll a rug in the accepted manner.
  Walk to the area of the room containing the tower of cubes.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Sounds</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/articles/key-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/articles/key-sounds/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;There are 40 key sounds, or phonemes, taught in the Montessori early childhood classroom.  24 are represented by one symbol and 16 by a double symbol.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The three period lesson is used to introduce and practice these sounds with the sandpaper letters.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Period Lesson</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/articles/three-period-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/articles/three-period-lesson/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The three period lesson is an integral part of the Montessori curriculum.  This lesson was originated by Edouard Seguin during the mid-19th century in France.   The three  period lesson is used in the 3-6 classroom to help children learn a variety of vocabulary including color names, numeral names, sandpaper letter sounds, and sight words.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>