<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Articles on Miss Amanda</title>
    <link>http://missamanda.blog/articles/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Articles on Miss Amanda</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 19:02:40 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://missamanda.blog/articles/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>The Three Period Lesson</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/articles/three-period-lesson/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 31 Mar 2020 19:02:40 -0700</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/articles/three-period-lesson/</guid>
      <description>The three period lesson is an integral part of the Montessori curriculum. This lesson was originated by Edouard Seguin during the mid-19th century in France. The three period lesson is used in the 3-6 classroom to help children learn a variety of vocabulary including color names, numeral names, sandpaper letter sounds, and sight words.
In simple terms, the three steps, or periods, are
  Name (Introduce) &amp;ldquo;This is red.&amp;rdquo;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Key Sounds</title>
      <link>http://missamanda.blog/articles/key-sounds/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://missamanda.blog/articles/key-sounds/</guid>
      <description>There are 40 key sounds, or phonemes, taught in the Montessori early childhood classroom. 24 are represented by one symbol and 16 by a double symbol.
The three period lesson is used to introduce and practice these sounds with the sandpaper letters.
   Graphic Symbol: Sound:     a apple   b bear   c cookie   d dog   e egg   f fish   g gum   h hug   i in   j jump   k kick   l leg   m man   n net   o otter   p pig   r run   s sit   t tub   u up   v van   w wag   x ax   y yell   z zip   ai rain   ee see   ie pie   oa boat   ue cue   qu quit   sh ship   ch chin   th thumb   oy boy   ar car   or fork   er her   ou out   oo book   au August    </description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>